A Guide to the W. Graham Claytor Papers, 1912-1964
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
W. Graham Claytor Papers, 1912-1964
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1981-095
3.0 cu. ft. 6 boxes
Business and personal papers of W. Graham Claytor, a 1906 graduate of Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College (now Virginia Tech) and an executive overseeing the operations of a number of American Gas and Electric Company subsidiaries during the 20th century. Includes correspondence, reports, and printed materials relating to personal financial matters, business operations, Virginia Polytechnic Institute, and ham radio.
Claytor, W. Graham
Contents List
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The W. Graham Claytor Papers were donated to Special Collections in 1981.
Biographical Note
William Graham Claytor, son of Graham and Marion Bell Claytor, was born in Bedford, Virginia on December 20, 1886. More familiarly known by his middle name, Graham Claytor matriculated at Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College (later Virginia Tech) as an electrical engineering student in 1902. Following his father's death, Claytor left school in his junior year to work as a student engineer in General Electric's Lynn, Massachusetts testing plant. In 1907, Claytor accepted a position with the Roanoke Railway and Electric Company as a salesman; in 1908, he was appointed an electrical engineer. That same year, Claytor married Gertrude Harris Boatwright, a Virginia poet. The couple would have three sons.
Through successive promotions, Claytor had become general superintendent of Roanoke Railway and Electric and the Lynchburg Traction and Light Company by 1914. His career on temporary hold while serving as a captain in the U.S. Army Quartermaster Corps from 1918 to 1919, Claytor afterward resumed his previous position and in 1923, was named chief engineer for American Electric Power Company of Philadelphia. In 1926, Claytor became the company's general manager. The following year, the company was purchased by American Gas and Electric Company of New York. Claytor was transferred to New York City and appointed vice president and director of a number of the company's subsidiaries, including Appalachian Electric Power Company, Kentucky and West Virginia Power Company, West Virginia Power Company, Radford Limestone Corporation, and Franklin Real Estate Company. As vice president of Appalachian Power, Claytor directed construction of the Appalachian Power Company's dam on the New River in Pulaski County, Virginia. Completed in 1939, the dam created Claytor Lake, named in his honor. Claytor retired in 1954, but returned to serve as executive vice president of American Electric Power from 1960. After retiring from American Electric again in 1962, he continued to serve as president of Richardson-Wayland Electric Corporation (Roanoke, Virginia).
Claytor remained an ardent supporter of his alma mater and in the 1950s served on the board of directors of both the VPI Alumni Association and the VPI Educational Foundation. Chief among Claytor's other interests was ham radio, a hobby he pursued for more than 25 years. Following his 1962 retirement, Claytor resided in the cottage he had built on Claytor Lake. Graham Claytor died in Roanoke February 28, 1971, and was buried in Evergreen Burial Park, Roanoke, Virginia.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the business and personal papers of Graham Claytor, a 1906 graduate of Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College (later Virginia Polytechnic Institute) and an executive overseeing the operations of a number of American Gas and Electric Company subsidiaries during the 20th century. Included are such materials as correspondence, printed materials, financial statements, reports, and photographs.
A large portion of the collection consists of materials relating to routine personal financial matters, including stock holdings, insurance, bank accounts, and philanthropy. The collection also includes correspondence with politicians, business associates, company employees, and personal friends, with discussions of business and personal matters often overlapping within a single letter. Also regarding Claytor's affiliation with American Gas and Electric are files specifically relating to company operations, speeches made by Claytor, and promotional printed materials.
The single most predominant subject in the collection is Virginia Polytechnic Institute. The materials document Claytor's contacts with other alumni and his membership in the Virginia Tech Alumni Association - New York Chapter. The focus of the files, however, is on Claytor's service on the boards of directors of the VPI Alumni Fund and the VPI Educational Foundation (later, Virginia Tech Foundation). Of particular interest, perhaps, are materials relating to the establishment of the foundation and fundraising efforts for Virginia Tech's War Memorial Chapel and Memorial Court.
The collection also contains several files relating to Claytor's interest in ham radio. Included are correspondence with other ham radio operators, printed materials from dealers and manufacturers, and technical specifications.
Arrangement
The collection essentially retains Claytor's original, alphabetical filing system, though a few items have been moved for the sake of consistency, and a few files previously labeled "miscellaneous" and housed at the end have been interfiled with the remainder of the collection. The arrangement retains a quirk in that some materials are filed by subject matter, while others are filed by correspondent name, apparently depending on which Claytor thought was the more significant at the time. Correspondence relating to a single subject may therefore be spread among the file entries for a number of individuals.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Local/Regional History and Appalachian South; Railroad; Science and Technology; University Archives; University History; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Aa-Al (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Abbot, John L., 1938-1950
  - Academy of Political Science, 1951, n.d.
  - Adams, Holcombe C., 1951
  - Adamson, A. V., 1948
  - Adamson, Learoyd, 1946, n.d.
  - Adelphi College, 1953-1954
  - Admirals of the Flagship Fleet, 1951
  - Aetna Life Insurance Company, 1943-1952
  - Air conditioning, 1937-1948
  - Albergotti, Robert Buckner, 1944
- Am, [2 folders] (Box-folder 1-2)
  - American Assembly, 1952
  - American Electric Power System Management Meeting, 1967, n.d.
  - American Gas and Electric Company, 1945-1957, n.d.
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1938-1952, n.d.
  - American Red Cross, 1950-1951, n.d.
  - Amos, O'Neal, 1951-1952
- An-Ar (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Anthony, Graham, 1942
  - Appalachian Power Company, 1938-1961, n.d.
  - Arco Electric Supply Company, 1949
  - Argabrite, Newt M. 1949-1952
  - Armistead, Allen B. 1953
  - Armpriester, Charles W., 1949
- As-Az (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Ashforth, Albert B., Inc., 1948
  - Associated Hospital Service of New York, 1937-1951, n.d.
  - Associated Industries of Kentucky, 1950
  - Atlantic City Electric Company, 1947-1949
  - Atlantic Hardware and Supply Company, 1952
  - Atomic Energy Commission, 1951-1952, n.d.
  - Attwood, Frederic, 1943-1945
  - Auto accident, 1934
  - Avrack, J. Albert, 1946
  - Ayer, N. W. and Son, Inc., 1948, n.d.
- Ba-Bo (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Babcock and Wilcox Company, 1947
  - Babin Boiler Service, 1944
  - Bachrach, 1954
  - Bainbridge, Kimpton and Haupt, Inc., 1949
  - Baldwin, Charles L. Jr., 1940
  - Ball, Ben, 1949
  - Ball, Benson (Mrs.), 1948
  - Ball, ____, 1944
  - Barnes, James E., 1936
  - Barrow, Joe, 1944
  - Battle, John S., 1954
  - Beard, William K, 1936-1954
  - Bedford County Memorial Hospital Building Fund, 1950, n.d.
  - Berinati Press, 1937-1940
  - Berry, Orville, 1933
  - Berry Schools, 1950
  - Black, Ficher, 1948
  - Black Sign Maple Syrup Company, 1943
  - Blair, J. Jacob, 1944
  - Blewett, William E. Jr., 1952
  - Blue Diamond Service Corporation, 1933
  - Boatwright, Gertrude H., 1931-1948
  - Bobbitt, Walter B. (Radford Limestone Company), 1944-1954
  - Boca Raton Club, 1948
  - Bondurant, J. C., 1936
- Bp-Bz (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Breakell, James, 1942
  - Brenner, Butler and McVeigh, 1951-1952, n.d.
  - Brown, W. E., 1941-1942
  - Buchanan, W. A., 1949
  - Buckley, William, 1948
  - Buford, Paul C., 1940
  - Burchill, Joseph M., 1941
  - Bureau of Motor Vehicles (New York), 1946-1952
  - Bureau of Vital Statistics (Virginia), 1947
  - Burger, Milan, 1948
  - Burger, R. E., 1948-1954
  - Burks, Martin, 1948
  - Burleson, W. H., 1943
  - Burress, J. W., 1954
  - Burton, Clarence, 1949
  - Butler, Mary, 1944
  - Byllesby and Buck hydroelectric plant - group photograph and list of visitors, 1912
  - Byrd, Harry F., 1935-1952, n.d.
- Ca-Claytoq (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Calvert, Carl C., 1949
  - Carlton House, 1952
  - Casabona, Bettina, 1954
  - Cemeteries (Bedford, Virginia), 1949
  - Central Operating Company, 1953
  - Chamber of Commerce (Roanoke, Virginia), 1953-1954
  - Chandler, Albert B., 1954
  - Christmas card list, n.d.
  - Clark, James Albon, 1951
  - Clay, Lucius D., 1953
  - Clayton, James, 1933-1942, n.d.
- Claytor A-L (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Claytor family (California), 1945, n.d.
  - Claytor Lake, 1941-1959, n.d.
  - Claytor Lake property and cottage, 1950-1954, n.d.
- Claytor M-Z (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Claytor, Richard, 1952
  - Claytor, W. Graham, 1933-1952, n.d.
  - Claytor, W. Graham Jr., 1947
  - Claytor, William G. (Bedford, Virginia), 1947
- Claytos-Cz (Box-folder 1-10)
  - Cochocton Chamber of Commerce, 1948
  - Collins, Lewis Preston, 1950
  - Columbia University, 1952
  - Cook, Philip F., 1936
  - Cotten, Bob, 1949
  - Cotton, Edwin R., 1954
  - Cotton, Preston, 1952
  - Coudert, Frederic R. Jr., 1949
  - Cox, Oscar W., 1949
  - Coxe, M. F., 1946
  - Craig, Annie, 1946
  - Crannell, Nugent and Kranzer, Inc., 1951
  - Crumb, K. B., 1946
  - Cryder, James W., 1950-1951
  - Cutright, H. G., 1953
- D (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Dalton, Ted, 1950-1954, n.d.
  - Daniel, Robert H., 1953
  - Darrah, A. J., 1948-1950
  - Davey, Martin L. Jr., 1947-1949
  - Dazey Churn and Manufacturing Company, 1947
  - De Treville, Ruth Saffold, 1941-1942, n.d.
  - Deahl, Jessie, 1947-1948
  - Deepwater Power Plant, 1927-1934
  - Deering John G., 1951
  - Diamond AGE Association, 1944-1951, n.d.
  - Dickerman, Judson C., 1938-1942
  - Diet, 1940
  - Dietz Press, 1948
  - Dixon, E. H., 1949
  - Dowdy, Roy C., 1948-1953
  - Doyle, R. E., 1952
  - Draper, Claude L., 1949-1953
  - Draper, John S., 1953
  - Dreier, Thomas, 1947
  - Dubilier, William, 1947
  - Duffy, B. C., 1948
  - Dunn, G. S., 1952
  - Dunning, E. R., 1954
  - Dzwonczyk, V. L., 1952
- E (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Eastman Kodak Company, 1949-1952
  - Edison Electric Institute, 1950
  - Eily, Carrie, 1945
  - Electric range, 1945
  - Electrical Communication subscription, 1947, n.d.
  - Elliott, Davis, 1950
  - Employee Information Program (American Gas and Electric Service Corporation), [1952], n.d.
  - Engineers' Investment Association, 1942
  - England, B. L., 1948-1952
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society, 1953
  - Erben, H. V., 1948
  - Erwin, E. D., 1952
  - Eudy, Mary Cummins, 1946
  - Evans, Flen J., 1953
- F (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Fargo Motor Corporation, 1947
  - Farr, John A., 1947
  - Federal Power Commission, 1935-1936, n.d.
  - Feldman, Robert H., 1947
  - Ferguson, Homer L., 1943-1951
  - Ferrell, R. W., 1951
  - Ficklen, W. F., 1948
  - Fields, Ernest S., 1954
  - Firearms exhibit (Herman P. Dean Arms Collection), n.d.
  - First National Exchange Bank of Roanoke, 1932-1939
  - Flanagan, James H., 1940-1941
  - Flowers, Mary, 1944
  - Fox, Edward C., 1938-1947, n.d.
  - Frost, R. J. "Jack," 1941-1951
  - Funk, M. C., 1947-1951
  - Furr, Guy Littleton "Fuzzy," 1946-1952
  - Furr, Guy Littleton Jr., 1953
- Ga-Gt (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Gatchell, Willard, 1943-1954, n.d.
  - General Electric, 1947-1953
  - Gills, James P., 1946-1954
  - Gilman, W. C. and Company, 1949
  - Gordon, Herbert, 1942-1953
  - Graham, Charles V., 1952
  - Gray, H. O., 1954
  - Gresham, L. G., 1950
  - Griffin, Frederick, R. III, 1954
  - Grimsley, A. H., 1949
  - General Precision Equipment, 1959
  - Griscom Russell Company, 1958-1959
- Gu-Gz (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1944-1954
  - Guill, George, 1949
  - Gulf States Utilities Company, 1947-1953
- Ha-Hh (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Haller, William G., 1948
  - Halpin, Dan, 1948
  - Hancock, Grace, 1952, n.d.
  - Hancock, John W., 1946-1953
  - Hancock, John W. Jr., 1942-1952, n.d.
  - Hand, Learned, 1943
  - Handy, John T. Company, 1947-1953
  - Hartford Electric Light Company, 1944, n.d.
  - Haslam, R. T., 1952
  - Hay, Eugenia C., 1946-1954, n.d.
  - Hayes, H. R., 1950
- Hi-Hor (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Higgins, A. W., 1947
  - Hill, J. Calvin, 1960
  - Hodges, Marian, 1949-1954
  - Hodges, R. E. "Dick," 1947-1948
  - Hogan, Arnold, 1946-1959
  - Holden, Raymond, 1946
  - Holtzclaw, J. G., 1945
  - Hoover Report, 1949, n.d.
  - Horn, Fraser, 1949
- Hos, [2 folders] (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Hospital stay, 1950, n.d.
  - Hospitalization, 1940-1948
- Hot-Hoz, [2 folders] (Box-folder 2-9)
  - Howell, Clifton H. (Radford Limestone Company), 1933-1947
- Hp-Hz (Box-folder 2-10)
  - Hughes, Bob, 1953
  - Hurt, R. N., 1952, n.d.
  - Hutchinson, Rivinus and Company, 1936-1954
- Ia-Inc (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Ickes, Harold L., 1934
  - Ide, Charles E., 1949
  - Income tax, 1947-1951, n.d.
- Ind-Iz (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Indiana and Michigan Electric Company, 1950, n.d.
  - Indianapolis Star and News, 1948
  - Inn, The (Biddeford Pool, Maine), 1945, n.d.
  - Insurance Company of North America, 1952, n.d.
  - Interlaken Inn, n.d.
  - Interlocking positions, 1940-1941
  - Iron Worker, 1947-1951
- J (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Jackson, John Early, 1933-1942
  - Jackson, Raymond T., 1935
  - Jennings, Croft, 1944
  - Jennings, Lawrence "Larry," 1945-1952
  - Jennison, Ralph D., 1943
  - Jewell, R. R., 1949
  - Jewett, John M. "Jack," 1949, n.d.
  - John, Grace Spaulding, 1953
  - Johnson, Eliza, 1941
  - Johnston, Clement D., 1949
  - Juror summons, 1942
- K (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Kalette, M. E., 1946
  - Kee, Elizabeth, 1951-1953, n.d.
  - Kee, John, 1935
  - Kerite Company, 1948, n.d.
  - Kerschner, Edward, 1947, n.d.
  - Kerschner, Edward Jr., 1938, n.d.
  - Ketterer, Ann, 1948
  - Ketterer, John G., 1952
  - King, J. H. "Hal," 1948
  - Kirkeby Hotels, n.d.
  - Kuylenstierna, A. Julius, 1933-1943
  - Kyle, W. D., 1940-1954
- L (Box-folder 3-5)
  - Lane, F. A. 1952
  - Lang, Chester H., 1953
  - Larkin, Roosevelt and Larkin, 1942
  - Lawrence, J. D., 1948-1954
  - Lawrence, M. P. 1950
  - Lawton, Frank B., 1938
  - Lawton, Mabel A., 1938, n.d.
  - Lawton, William J., 1938
  - Lee, Claudius, 1952, n.d.
  - Legal Aid Society, 1949
  - Line Material Company, 1949-1950
  - Lineweaver, G. W., n.d.
  - Link, Fred M., 1937
  - Livingston, Von E., 1947-1948
  - Logan, Douglas, 1953
  - Lowmaster, A. T., 1938
  - Luce, Donald C., 1948
  - Lunsford Sons and Izard Insurance, 1934-1953
- Ma-Mn (Box-folder 3-6)
  - Macabe, Helen, n.d.
  - Macabe, T. J., 1938
  - MacLane, J. F., 1952, n.d.
  - Malley, Patricia, 1948
  - Mariners' Museum, n.d.
  - Markle, H., 1944-1945
  - Marks, Herbert, 1949-1950
  - Matthews, A. R., 1953-1954, n.d.
  - Maxwell, John, 1945-1946
  - May, Vera I., 1948
  - McCoy, William V., 1953
  - McGraw, Max, 1951-1952
  - McNinch, Frank R., 1937
  - McWane, Henry E., 1952
  - Meadows, C. W., 1948
  - Merrill, A. S., 1944-1946
  - Messick, Warren, 1953
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, 1942-1952
  - Metten, John F. "Jack," 1944-1947
  - Miles, George Jr., 1949
  - Military Order of the Purple Heart, n.d.
  - Miller, A. D., 1957
  - Minichan, D. P., 1948-1951
  - Mir, Flora, 1949
  - Mitchell, Sydney A., 1953
- Mo-Mz (Box-folder 3-7)
  - Moomaw, B. F., 1945
  - Mooney, Joe, 1950
  - Moore, Charles E., 1954
  - Moore, L. Franklin, 1943-1947
  - Moore, Junius T., 1950
  - Moorehead, Ludwig K., 1947-1948, n.d.
  - Moorhead, D. G., 1949-1952
  - Morin, C. B., 1953, n.d.
  - Mortimer, C. Roy, 1944-1953
  - Moseley, Sherrard, 1939-1940
  - Mount Holly Garage, 1952
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1950
  - Music Research Foundation, 1947-1953, n.d.
- N (Box-folder 3-8)
  - Nagele, F. G., 1950
  - National City Bank of New York, 1928-1953
  - National Resources Planning Board, 1950, n.d.
  - Neubauer, Bob, 1947
  - New Jersey State Federation of Labor, 1948
  - New River case, 1947, n.d.
  - New York Life Insurance Company, 1935-1952
  - New York Southern Society, 1946-1947
  - New York State Electric and Gas Corporation, 1943
  - New York Telephone Company, 1941-1943, n.d.
  - New York Times, 1949
  - Niagara Frontier Planning Board, 1940
  - Nicholson, John E., 1949
  - Nickel Plate Road, 1948
  - Noland, L. U. "Casey," 1940-1947
- O (Box-folder 3-9)
  - O'Brien Sales Corporation, 1945
  - Ohio Congressional representatives, [1949]
  - Ohio Edison Company, 1949
  - Ohio Power Company, 1950, n.d.
  - Ohio Valley Board of Trade, 1950
  - Old First Company, Virginia Coast Artillery, n.d.
  - Oliver, Robert B., 1950
  - Ormond, Roy B. 1936-1951
  - Otey, Ernest G., 1953-1954
  - Ould, E. H., 1953-1954
  - Overstreet, J. W., 1954
- P-Q (Box-folder 3-10)
  - Painter, B. D., 1947-1948
  - Palmer, Arthur, 1947
  - Parker, T. M., 1951
  - Parsons, D. W., 1949
  - Pebbleford Distillery Company, 1948
  - Peek, W. S., 1949
  - Perry, Hunter, 1942-1945, n.d.
  - Pick, Lewis A., 1950, n.d.
  - Pilot Club, 1949-1951, n.d.
  - Pinckney, J., 1950
  - Pistol license (New York), 1940-1952
  - Pocahontas Fuel Company, 1947
  - Poems, 1949, n.d.
  - Police complaint (New York), 1948
  - Pomerene, Warren M., 1947-1954
  - Potter, Edwin E., 1952
  - Poysky, Edward, 1953
  - Preston, Kathryn, 1951-1952
  - Princeton University Library, 1952
  - Proctor, C. L., 1944-1949
  - Pulaski County Chamber of Commerce, 1954
  - Purdue University, 1946
  - Purdy, Francis "Mike," 1946
  - Purrington, Helen C., 1940-1941
- Raa-Rah, [4 folders] (Box-folder 3-11-4-1)
  - Radio (Ham), 1936-1964, n.d.
- Rai (Box-folder 4-2)
  - Railroad-Machinery Club of New York, 1946-1954, n.d.
- Raj-Rn (Box-folder 4-3)
  - Rayburn bill (Public Utility Act of 1935), 1935
  - Read, Granville M., 1950
  - Reconstruction Finance Corporation, 1945
  - Reese, Everett. D., 1954
  - Reid, _____ 1945-1954
  - Rhodes, H. W., 1938
  - Richards, H. Moore, 1940
  - Richardson-Wayland Electrical Corporation, 1918-1954, n.d.
- Ro-Rz (Box-folder 4-4)
  - Roanoke Country Club, 1942-1952
  - Roanoke, Virginia - real estate taxes, 1932-1953, n.d.
  - Roanoke World News, 1950
  - Roberson, Curtis, 1947-1954
  - Roberts, W. S., 1941
  - Robertson, A. Willis, 1947-1950, n.d.
  - Robertson, William P., 1942-1943
  - Rogers Peet Company, 1949
  - Rose, _____ 1950
  - Royal-Eastern Electrical Supply Company, 1953
  - Ruffin, Peter B., 1948-1950
  - Rumsey, George A., 1948-1949
- Sa-Sd (Box-folder 4-5)
  - St. Luke's Hospital, 1942-1948
  - Salvation Army, 1947-1949, n.d.
  - Sammis, Walter, 1942-1944
  - Sanders, Claytor, 1936
  - Sanders, Lucy, 1936, n.d.
  - Sands Point Golf Club, 1941-1942
  - Sawyer, R. Tom, 1948
  - Sawyer, Willits H., 1948-1949
  - Schenck, Pansy, 1951, n.d.
  - Schley, Frederic C., 1945-1946
  - Schmidt, Henry G., 1949
  - Sclater, I. H., 1938-1949
- Se-Sg (Box-folder 4-6)
  - Seabrook Farms Company, 1949
  - Sears Roebuck and Company, 1947, n.d.
  - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1937-1954
  - Security Analysts, New York Society of, 1951
  - Seven Gables Bookshop, 1950
  - Seymour, Frederick D., 1952
- Sh-Sped (Box-folder 4-7)
  - Shedd, Fred, 1948
  - Sheraton Hotel (Boston, Massachusetts), 1949
  - Sidur, Marguerite, 1937
  - Sidur, Robert Alexander, 1939-1954, n.d.
  - Siebrecht, Alice, 1943
  - Sliter, H. M., 1949
  - Slocum, Harry Spencer, 1941-1949, n.d.
  - Slover, S. L., 1939
  - Smith, George Otis, 1936
  - Smith, R. H., 1954, n.d.
  - Smith, W. H., 1941
  - Social Security, 1936-1949
  - Sollitt, Ralph, 1948
  - Sorenson, C. V., 1947-1953, n.d.
  - Southeastern Electric Exchange, 1950
  - Sowle, Harry, 1951
  - Spear, L. Y. "Willy," 1944-1947, n.d.
- Spee, [2 folders] (Box-folder 4-8)
  - Speeches, 1951-1953, n.d.
- Spef-Ss, [2 folders] (Box-folder 5-1)
  - Sporn, Philip, 1947-1960, n.d.
  - Sprague, Frank Julian, 1948-1953
- Sta-Stn (Box-folder 5-2)
  - Stanley, W. F., 1943
  - Stansbury, H. A., 1941, n.d.
  - Stearns, Florence D., 1953, n.d.
  - Steele, R. B., 1945
  - Stephenson, Walter G., 1938
  - Stereo Slide Service, 1952
  - Sterling, J. Loren, 1947
  - Sterling, Lee, 1949-1954, n.d.
  - Stevens, R. G., 1947, n.d.
  - Stevenson, T. Kennedy, 1952-1954
  - Stewart, Robert, 1946
  - Stillman, Hugh D., 1953
- Stoa-Stoj, [2 folders] (Box-folder 5-3)
  - Stocks, 1947-1954, n.d.
- Stok-Sz (Box-folder 5-4)
  - Stoke, H. F., 1936-1949
  - Stone, Edward L. (Stone Printing and Manufacturing Company), 1935
  - Strain, W. C. (Radford Limestone Company), 1938-1940
  - Sutton, Louis V., 1948, n.d.
  - Swanson, Dale H., 1947-1949
  - System disturbance, 1950
- T-U (Box-folder 5-5)
  - Tabor, C. H., 1941
  - Taylor, Charles, 1943, n.d.
  - Taylor, John M., 1950
  - Thomas, Margaret Loring, 1953
  - Thompson Street Garage, 1952
  - Thompson, W. C. Garage (Biddeford, Maine), 1942
  - Thornburg, C. A., 1948
  - Tice, William, 1949
  - Tidd, George N., 1945-1949
  - Torchio, Philip, 1947-1952, n.d.
  - Torrey, Carl E., 1941
  - Travelers Aid Society, 1941-1953
  - Travelers Insurance, 1937-1941
  - Troy, M. O., 1938
  - Turner, Harold, 1946-1953, n.d.
  - Tynes, Buford C., 1951
  - Underwood and Underwood, 1944, n.d.
  - Union Fishermens Co-operative, 1953, n.d.
  - United Air Lines, 1941
  - United States Casualty Company, 1943, n.d.
  - United States Treasury Dept., 1944
  - Universal Signal Appliances Company, n.d.
  - University of Virginia Graduate School of Business, 1952, n.d.
- Va-Virginia O (Box-folder 5-6)
  - Veterans Administration, 1945-1954, n.d.
  - Virginia Bridge Company, 1938
  - Virginia Coal and Coke Company, 1954
  - Virginia Electric and Power Company, 1938-1951
  - Virginia Historical Society, 1952, n.d.
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute - alumni, 1936-1963, n.d., [5 folders] (Box-folder 5-7)
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute Educational Foundation, 1948-1954, n.d., [4 folders] (Box-folder 6-1)
- Virginia Polytechnic Institute - general, 1938-1959, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 6-2)
- Virginia Q-Vz (Box-folder 6-3)
  - Virginia State Commission on Conservation and Development, 1938, n.d.
  - Virginia State Corporation Commission, 1950
  - Virginians, The, 1952-1953
  - Virginias Seniors Golf Association, 1940-1953
- Wa-Whe (Box-folder 6-4)
  - Wade, Charlie 1947
  - Wagenhals, E., 1943-1947, n.d.
  - Waldo, Marion, 1946
  - Waldo, Paul V. W., 1944
  - Walker, Thomas P., 1947
  - Ward, N. Floyd, 1941-1942
  - Washington, Booker T. Birthplace Memorial, 1947, n.d.
  - Washington Square Association, 1934
  - Watson, E. Alban, 1952
  - Way, Asa P., 1947
  - Wellford, Armstead L., 1951
  - Werth, Bogardus, 1951
  - Werth, James Robert, 1947-1951
  - Werth, Pauline, 1947
  - West Penn Power Company, 1953
  - Wheelock, John Hall, 1953
- Whf-Wn (Box-folder 6-5)
  - White, Bryant, 1935-1950
  - White, Charles M. Jr., 1941-1942
  - Whitefield, W. I., 1938-1948
  - Whittington, Will M., 1950
  - Who's Who in Transportation and Communication, 1942
  - Wildman, Eunice, 1948
  - Wildman, Loyd, 1943-1948
  - Williams, E. B., 1947
  - Williams, Harrison, 1953
  - Williams, R. Gray, 1942
- Wo-Wz (Box-folder 6-6)
  - Wood, Charles P., 1954
  - Wood, W. E., 1947
  - Woodcock, Floyd W., 1943-1953, n.d.
  - Woodrum, Clifton A., 1935-1948, n.d.